# Polycarp N. C. Anyanwu

Software Developer/Project Manager

## **Executive Summary**

An experienced programmer that had developed enterprise applications using Java, ADF, Oracle SQL, Microsoft SQL Server, and Microsoft.Net. Proven leader with Project Management certification (PMP) with vast experience managing teams of developers. Presently upskilling for Full Stack Software development and completed the HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python and Bootstrap courses from the Code Institute Dublin with three projects available at my GitHub page. Also studying cloud technologies starting with Microsoft Azure.

## **Employment History**

Head ICT Department at National Pension Commission Nigeria, Abuja Nigeria January 2006 — July 2021

- Developed capacity for application development and has lead teams that designed and developed industry wide applications:
  - Enhanced Registration Application (ECRS) online data submission system used to register participants in the Contributory pension systems in Nigeria
  - RSA Transfer Application (a clearing system used to transfer participants in the Contributory Pension System from one Pension Fund Administrator to another).
  - Performance Appraisal system with integrated examination module and Retiree enrollment application system.
- Coordinated activities, budget, strategy, projects, vision of the ICT Department.

ACB International Bank Plc March 2002 – January 2006 AGM/Head, Information Technology

- Coordinated activities of the Department
- Led ICT staff to support users of ICT resources
- Championed the implementation of Globus Banking application, its interfacing with third party applications, and change management processes.
- Worked with line managers to clarify business requirements and agree specifications for systems solutions.
- Vendor management

#### **Contact Details**

+353876941515 polyanyanwu@gmail.

#### Links

com

LinkedIn GitHub

#### Skills

HTML5

CSS3

Python3

JavaScript

Bootstrap

SQL

**Analytical Thinking** 

Strong problemsolving

Java/J2EE

Programming

Hackathon (Team work)

**Project Management** 

Self-Motivated

Software Logic

Software

Troubleshooting

Knowledgeable in User Interface/ User

Experience Database

Management

NAL Bank Plc. Aug 1997 – March 2002 (IT Department applications unit)

- Developed and implemented a Human Resource application using Visual Basic and SQL Server database
- Integration of banking application Equation DBA with the Payroll application.

Agile Methodology
Weblogic App Server
Oracle ADF

Placade Technologies Ltd, Lagos (May 1994 - July 1997) Applications Development.

- Developed Payroll Application using Visual Basic
- Trained clients on application development using Visual Basic
- Customer liaison & business development

#### **Education**

- Diploma in Full stack Software Development (Code Institute & UCD Dublin – September 2021 - date
- MBA Business Administration, Enugu State University of Science & Technology (ESUT), Enugu Nigeria --- August 1999 - June 2001
- M. Engr Computer Applications, Shanghai University of Technology, Shanghai, , Shanghai China -- November 1989 - June 1991
- B.Sc. Hons Computer Science (1st Class), University of Nigeria, Nsukka, Nsukka Nigeria -- October 1984 - June 1988

## **Certificates, Professional Qualifications**

- Project Management Professional (PMP).
- The Complete JavaScript Course: from Zero to hero (Aug 2021 Udemy)
- Leadership courses of Kellogg School of Management, Evanston Illinois, USA
- Advanced Java Programming Developing SOAP Web Service (Aug 2019) Intertech Minneapolis, USA
- ITIL Expert

#### Languages

English, Igbo, basic Chinese.